Mujeeb Rahman Melevilakkathil

Senior full stack developer | Front-end dev lead | Solution designer

Location: Melbourne

ABOUT ME

A creative technology enthusiast and Senior Full Stack developer with more than 15 years of experience in creating Hybrid Apps and pixel perfect websites. I derive great joy in learning new technologies and providing solutions. I am seeking new challenging opportunities, especially in web technologies that will enable me to acquire new skills.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- 15+ years of experience in Web/Mobile application development using HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- 10+ years of experience in SPA development using JavaScript frameworks/libraries such as jQuery, Angular JS, Angular2/4, Knockout JS, Durandal JS, React JS, Redux.
- Experience in designing solutions for Front-end, middleware applications and Microservices.
- Extensive experience in React JS and working with React Redux Saga architecture.
- Strong working experience in Angular JS and Angular.
- 7 years of experience in Agile development methodology.
- Extensive experience in Banking domain.

FONT-END BACKEND 5 HTML5/CSS3/JAVASCRIPT - 14 YEARS PHP & MYSQL - 4 YEARS ANGULARJS - 4 YEARS NODEJS/EXPRESS/GRAPHQL - 2 YEARS ANGULAR 2 - 6 MONTHS SOFTWARE DEVELOPEMENT MODELS JS REACTJS - 2 YEARS JS DURANDAL/KNOCKOUTJS - 4 YEARS **™** WATERFALL **DOMAINS TOOLS** Ju DATA VISUALIZATION ☐ CORDOVA ENERGY **BANKING** See CSS PREPROCESSOR(SASS, LESS) ♣ SOCIAL NETWORKING BUILD AUTOMATION(WEBPACK, GULP) **CAREER SUMMARY** Tata Consultancy Services Software Prod & Plat Eng Manager | Solution Designer **Assistant Consultant** 613 613 Aug 2021 - CURRENT | Sydney Apr 2012 - Aug 2021 | Kochi, Sydney, Melbourne Cabot Technology Solutions Megatrend Systems Senior Software Developer Software Engineer 613 613 Jun 2008 - Mar 2012 | Kochi Nov 2007 - Jun 2008 | Kochi

CAREER PROFILE



National Australia Bank - Solution designer | Front-end dev lead

Accenture | Sydney, Australia

Provided an End-to-End solution for NAB bankers which will help them to create a term deposit account for customers within minutes and a few clicks. The application was a standalone application that can easily be plugged into the banker dashboard.

HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript React GraphQL NodeJS Typescript Rally KafKa REST APIs



St George Bank - Senior Front-End Developer

Tata Consultancy Services | Sydney, Australia

Designed and delivered one reusable component for SSO by using PKCE oAuth2 concepts and the same is used to launch external systems from Mobile Banking and Internet banking application. The component is orchestrated in the front-end using plain JavaScript to communicate with Identity Provider. This component helped a huge number of customers to access their external file system and reward points swiftly.

HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript Durandal KnockoutJS Typescript JIRA Twitter Bootstrap LESS

MAR 2020 - SEP 2020

St George Bank - Customer Service Hub

Tata Consultancy Services | Sydney, Australia

Worked in a team to develop a faster experience for mortgage loan customers, the application helped customers to fill their loan applications in a limited number of interactions. The application uses React/Redux/Saga architecture in front-end and Nodejs as a middleware framework.

ReactJS Redux/saga Nodejs/express Jest Bamboo

AUG 2019 - NOV 2019

St George Bank - My Everyday Banking

Tata Consultancy Services | Sydney, Australia

Developed an application for switching customers to quickly import their payees and billers from their old bank. This application helped many new customers to import their Everyday Banking activities to the new bank. The application uses React/Redux/Saga architecture in front-end and Nodejs as a middleware framework.

ReactJS Redux/saga Nodejs/express Jest Bamboo



AGL One Minute Move - Senior Developer

Tata Consultancy Services | Melbourne, Australia

One Minute Move is an initiative to deliver a new online experience for new and existing customers who are moving home. It is a web application built on Angular 2 and later upgraded to Angular 4. Responsible for integrating Live person chat and ensuring 100% code coverage through unit testing and end-to-end testing.

HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript Angular 2/4 Knockout.js ASP.NET Sitecore JIRA Bamboo Octopus



TCS.com - Tech Lead

Tata Consultancy Services | Kochi, Kerala

TCS.com is the new face of TCS. The website which is built on pure JavaScript to ensure high performance. Created breathtaking CSS animations without using any third-party libraries.

HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript Meterializecss RWD

JAN 2016 - JUL 2016

SADAD Person-to-Person App - Solution Architect

Tata Consultancy Services | Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

SADAD P2P is a hybrid application rolled out for the Saudi Arabian Monetary Agency, which enables the customer of any associate bank can transfer money to any other associate bank customer using their phone number. As a solution architect, I was entrusted to provide a foolproof banking application with an emphasis in mitigating, finding, and resolving security risks related to hybrid applications. Responsibilities also included making contributions towards application architecture, conducting discussions with all stakeholders, provide up to date status for all stakeholders, and providing technical support to the offshore team. The main challenges faced in this project were security risks in Hybrid applications and time-boxed delivery. I have developed Cordova libraries for binary protection, jailbreak/routed detection, etc.

AngularJs HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript JQuery RWD Cordova pure.css Arxan Elastic Search

MAY 2013 - JAN 2016

TCS BaNCS Digital Suites - Tech Lead

Tata Consultancy Services | Kochi, Kerala

Tata Consultancy Services | Kochi, Kerala TCS BaNCS Digital suite is an enterprise-wide solution developed in Angular JS that enables bank to give customers the flexibility and convenience of managing their finances anywhere. It consists of both Mobile and Web application and compatible with different form factors and platforms. The solution is easily deployable and scalable and caters to retail and corporate banking (focused on small and medium businesses (SMBs)). Researched on various frontend frameworks including Backbone.js, ember.js and AngularJs to pick most suitable one for the product. The key responsibilities in this project is to understand the complete requirements of a hybrid application, provide a world-class solution, implement, and test the application. This product rolled out for multiple customers including Mercantile Bank South Africa, Bank Yahav Israel, and First Niagara Bank USA.

AngularJs HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript JQuery RWD Cordova



APR 2012 - MAY 2013

Hy5 Presidio - Module lead

Tata Consultancy Services | Kochi, Kerala

Hy5 Presidio is a Mobile device management tool that is used to track and manage mobile assets in an enterprise. Assigned with leading the team and developing the self-service and admin portal. The technology stack includes Bootstrap and jQuery.

HTMI 5 JavaScript CSS 3 Bootstrap RWD JQuery (+UI/Mobile)



JAN 2009 - MAR 2012

Fan2Band - Senior Software Developer

Cabot Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd.| Kochi, Kerala

Fan2Band is a social web marketing solution that leverages social networks and peer-to-peer influence to spread brand awareness. As a senior developer assigned with responsibilities for designing architecture and identifying technology stack. Got the opportunity to develop the Facebook application using Facebook mark-up language(FBML).

PHP MySQL HTML JavaScript JQuery JQtouch,JQuery Mobile CSS Flex Nodejs

FBML(Facebook Markup Language)

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAINING

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Dec 2021 | Validation Number: 3JGMBWFDN2Q11Y9M



SAFe 4 Certified Practitioner

Aug 2017 | CERTIFICATE ID: 80742142-7481



Leading SAFe

Jun 2017 | elabor8



70-480 Certified programmer HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Dec 2012 | Microsoft



EDUCATION



2004 - 2007

Master of Computer Applications

University of Calicut



2001 - 2004

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

University of Calicut



APRIL 2001

STANDARD XII / H.S.C.

Board of HSE, Kerala Government

CONTACT INFO

Up on request

A copy of this resume can be viewed online @ https://mvmujeeb.github.io/cv